# DANIEL A. PINEDO

Phoenixville, PA 19460 | (215) 839-6299 | daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu | linkedin.com/in/odenipinedo/ | pinedo.org

### STATISTICAL CONSULTANT, STATISTICIAN

Trained statistician at the graduate level in the social sciences using the R language. Trusted statistical analyst and consultant with proven success collaborating with researchers to design, implement, analyze, and publish research and program evaluation. Use traditional/statistical, machine learning, network analysis, and data visualization approaches. Subject matter expertise in organizational behavior and mental health science, with emerging interests in psychiatric epidemiology, biostatistics, and urban planning. Maintain collegiality and sense of humor, cultivating cohesion and positive morale.

Technologies: R, Python, SPSS, Tableau – intermediate | Julia - beginner

### **EDUCATION**

CLAREMONT GRADUATE UNIVERSITY, Claremont, CA: Master of Arts (MA) in Organizational Behavior & Evaluation | 2020 SOFIA UNIVERSITY, Palo Alto, CA: Master of Arts (MA) in Clinical Psychology | 2013 NAROPA UNIVERSITY, Boulder, CO: Bachelor of Arts (BA) in Traditional Eastern Arts | 2010

## RECENT EXPERIENCE

LISA KACZMARCZYK PHD CONSULTING, LLC, Claremont, CA: **Statistical Consultant | 09/2019 – present** 

Initiated and created customized analysis tool based on social network theory, yielding high level of client satisfaction during intermediate program phase, with final program results and academic publication in preparation.

- Designed bespoke social network analysis tool used by client to narrate theory of change for large, complex client organization consisting of consortium of large universities instituting inter-disciplinary STEM program nationwide.
- Analyzed social network of cross-section of 3 attitudinal constructs across 3 university systems, including actor-event network graphs, interpretation consultation, and commented Rmarkdown script.
- Co-authored publication and poster presentation of final deliverable (see *curriculum vitae* for more information)

ACCENTURE PLC, CGU TALENT INNOVATION LAB, Claremont, CA: **Consultant | 11/2018 – 06/2020** Global HR / Recruitment Transformation Research & Development Lab

Managed project deliverable content and translated peer-reviewed organizational behavior research into business cases. Additional roles: project lead, project manager.

MOUNT SAINT MARYS UNIVERSITY, PSYCHOLOGY DEPARTMENT, Los Angeles, CA: Instructor | 01/2016 – 05/2018 Taught upper-division coursework in research methods, social psychology, and I/O psychology. Advised ten undergraduate students with 100% graduation rate.

- Quantitative methods in coursework: basic survey methods, correlation, χ2 categorical analysis, within-subjects design, between-subjects design, single subject design, single regression
- Qualitative methods in coursework: naturalistic observation, thematic content analysis
- Additional topics covered: research ethics, NIH human subjects training, APA format manuscript preparation using SPSS, introduction to R language, introduction to JMV (jamovi) graphical interface for R
- Coordination of symposium and opening speech on topic of importance of promoting undergraduate research and representation of women in STEM

Prior experience as mental health clinician, network operations engineer and IT consultant, 2007 – 2016

#### **PROJECTS**

GETTY LEADERSHIP INSTITUTE, LEAD LABS, Claremont, CA: Executive Coach | 05/2019 – 08/2019

Guided 3 senior international museum executives through intensive assessment center process during leadership training.

BOSTON CONSULTING GROUP GAMMA DATATHON, Los Angeles, CA: Team Lead | 03/2019 - 04/2019

Built and led cross-functional team of 5 experts in artificial intelligence, financial engineering, data science, management, and organizational behavior for invitation-only case competition for data analytics group of graduate students.

- Provided case formulation training, common strategy language, and high-level architecture for technical solution.
- Developed methodology to integrate ARIMA modeling/forecasting from financial engineering with cluster analysis and random forest classification from machine learning analysis, using publically available data.